SHANTNU AGGARWAL

Glasgow, UK (+44) 07825986995

shantnuagarwal1510@gmail.com

I am an MSc pursuing student from Glasgow Caledonian University with 3.5 years of professional experience in data modelling and management for a Sweden client. I am looking for part-time and Internship opportunities during my studies in data related fields.

EXPERIENCE

Infosys Limited, Jaipur

Senior Systems Engineer

May 2018 - Aug 2021

- Part of the Agile team that developed a staging database using SQL queries, PL/SQL functions and stored procedures employing various tools like SQL Developer, TOAD and ETL.
- Experience with Oracle REST Data Services (ORDS), which helps publish RESTful Web Services for interacting with the data and stored procedures in our database.
- Experience with UNIX Commands to access the database server hosted on a UNIX machine using tools like WinSCP and Putty.
- Experience working on POSTMAN to share, test, and document APIs, JMeter for load testing, used JIRA and KANBAN for work management and tracking, used ServiceNow to report and receive various requests and issues among the Enterprise.

Supra Industries Pvt. Ltd

Supervisor

June 2016 - Mar 2018

- Experience in quality testing and defect identification of finished iron products formed by the rolling process.
- Part of the inventory management team, which takes care of raw material purchase, testing, and approvals.
- Experience in interacting with clients, studying their requirements, and devising solutions.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (Mechanical Engineering)

2012 - 2016

Percentage: 67.34

- Presented a project on electricity generation through speed brakers using rack and pinion arrangement. The kinetic energy of the motion of speed brakers is converted to electricity.
- The main subjects included Mathematics where I learned topics such as linear programming and nonlinear optimization.

Secondary School, CBSE, New Delhi

2009-2010

Percentage: 88.4

Senior Secondary School, CBSE, New Delhi

2011-2012

Percentage: **81.6**

• The main subjects included Mathematics, Computer Science, Physics etc.

Relevant Technical Training:

 Prior to joining Infosys, I received 5 months of rigorous training on Programming fundamentals using Python, Data Structure DBMS, OOPS using python, from Global Education Centre at Infosys, Mysore.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Skills: PI/SQL, Oracle DB, Python, Tomcat, Maven, ServiceNow, Postman, Apache

JMeter, WinSCP, Putty, POSTMAN, ORDS, Agile, JIRA, Notepad ++,

Toad, SQL Developer, Junit, DBunit, utplsql

Operating Systems: Windows Server 2012, Windows 8.1, and Windows 10

Languages: Python, SQL, Java

OTHER INFORMATION

- Working with an NGO for past 6 years which helps in teaching the art of living, technical science, and spiritual values for youth.
- Branch coordinator of Indian society of technical Education (ISTE) where I headed more than 180 students and organized several events as a part of this.
- Organized various skits and drama events in Infosys and actively being part of them.
- Organized various events at the Technical Fest of college under SAE-India.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST